<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Design Course on Greeting.</title>
    <link>https://eterlan.github.io/tags/game-design-course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Design Course on Greeting.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 14:40:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://eterlan.github.io/tags/game-design-course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GameStoryWeek2</title>
      <link>https://eterlan.github.io/posts/2019/06/gamestoryweek2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 14:40:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eterlan.github.io/posts/2019/06/gamestoryweek2/</guid>
      <description>Instruction Pick a popular story or film that you are very familiar with. You are encouraged to use the same story or film you used in the Week 1 assignment. If not, you may choose a new film or story, but pick one you need not watch again for the purposes of this assignment. For this assignment, you are asked to begin fleshing out your selected film or story into a more detailed description for a possible game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GameStoryWeek3</title>
      <link>https://eterlan.github.io/posts/2019/06/gamestoryweek3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 14:40:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eterlan.github.io/posts/2019/06/gamestoryweek3/</guid>
      <description>Review About Idea Sheets In the previous lectures, we discussed creating Idea Sheets to generate ideas and thoughts on various aspects of your game story. These lists are for you to freestyle brainstorm thoughts onto paper to commit them to words, without judgement or hesitation. The concept is to allow yourself free-form creativity and just throw these ideas, however useful they may end up being, down on paper. As you may recall, the Idea Sheets I recommend are for the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jane and Jack</title>
      <link>https://eterlan.github.io/posts/2019/06/jane-and-jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 14:40:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eterlan.github.io/posts/2019/06/jane-and-jack/</guid>
      <description>Jane and Jack some thinking&amp;hellip;before the writing  no bad guys, think they have to do that. why you have to do that? robbory?killing is too much. why you have to do that? all about crime? something not allowed? illegel? thief. that&amp;rsquo;s bit better. what ? all crime? what about not moral ? that&amp;rsquo;s a lot better. why it always havr to be wrong? what about some unfortunate? or good=&amp;gt;bad=&amp;gt;good?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>